A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Rockefeller Boards, Series O FA324
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Rockefeller Brothers Fund
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation - 1958 Award Ceremonies, September-December 1958 (Box 22, Folder 222)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation - 1958 Award Ceremonies, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 223)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation - 1958 Award Ceremonies, 1960-1961 (Box 22, Folder 224)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation - Incorporation and By-Laws, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 225)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Special Studies, 1956-1957 (Box 22, Folder 226)
    Assembling of panels; drafts of reports. Plans and comments. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel.
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Special Studies, 1956-1957 (Box 22, Folder 0226A)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Special Studies, 1958-1960 (Box 23, Folder 227)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Special Studies - Overall Panel, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 228)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Certificate of Incorporation, 1940-1947 (Box 23, Folder 229)
    1956 and 1958 amendments to 1940 charter.
    88.1
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Incorporation and By-Laws, 1940-1961 (Box 23, Folder 230)
    Changes in By-Laws.
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Family Contributions, 1941-1961 (Box 23, Folder 231)
    Contributions by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Rockefeller Mauze. Discussion among Trustees about sharing of giving. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    88.2
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Family Contributions - Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1941-1955 (Box 23, Folder 232)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Family Contributions - David Rockefeller, 1941-1961 (Box 23, Folder 233)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Family Contributions - Winthrop Rockefeller, 1942-1949 (Box 23, Folder 234)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Family Contributions - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1941-1961 (Box 23, Folder 235)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Family Contributions - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1940-1961 (Box 23, Folder 236)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Family Contributions - Rodman C. Rockefeller, 1954 (Box 23, Folder 237)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Finance Committee - Minutes, 1941-1961 (Box 23, Folder 238)
    88.3
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Publicity and Clippings, 1940-1961 (Box 23, Folder 239)
    Press releases and newspaper clippings about Fund and its activities.
    88.4
- Rockefeller Foundation
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Proposed Foreign Mission Fund, 1906-1909 (Box 24, Folder 240)
    Original plans from which Foundation grew; plans of missionaries and Chinese experts regarding medical and educational missions in China. Correspondents include Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, George Foster, Ernest Burton, G. W. Knox, Robert Fitch, Arthur Smith.
    30
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Preliminary Organization of Foundation, 1906-1910 (Box 24, Folder 241)
    Plans for new organization for philanthropic giving.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Deed of Trust - Correspondence, 1909-1910 (Box 24, Folder 242)
    John D. Rockefeller's gift of Standard Oil stock to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; appointment of Frederick T. Gates and Harold McCormick as trustees of Foundation; charter and by-laws; revocation of deed of trust.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Minute Book, 1909-1910 (Box 24, Folder 243)
    Minute book of preliminary foundation.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Charter - Correspondence, 1907-1911 (Box 24, Folder 244)
    Attempts to obtain a charter; lobbying, opposition, changes in bill. Failure in United States Congress; success in New York State Assembly. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, Senator J. H. Gallinger, Senator J. C. Spooner, Senator N. Aldrich, C. W. Eliot.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Charter - U.S. Congress, 1911-1913 (Box 24, Folder 245)
    Senate and House bills, United States and New York; resolutions in support; hearings; reports.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Charter - New York Legislature, 1913 (Box 24, Folder 246)
    Copies of act; passage.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Charter - Jerome D. Greene - Correspondence, 1912-1913 (Box 24, Folder 247)
    Form letters and memoranda to senators.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Charter - Starr J. Murphy - Legal Memoranda, 1910 (Box 24, Folder 248)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Certificate of Incorporation, 1913 (Box 24, Folder 249)
    Certified copies of charter.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Certificate of Incorporation - Correspondence, 1912-1913 (Box 25, Folder 250)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Constitution, By-Laws, Amendments, 1916-1936 (Box 25, Folder 251)
    Copies; changes and proposed changes. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick, Roger S. Greene, Harry Pratt Judson, Edwin R. Embree, Norma S. Thompson.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Constitution, By-Laws, Amendments, 1938-1950 (Box 25, Folder 252)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Boylan Resolution to Repeal Charter, 1917-1925 (Box 25, Folder 253)
    State Senator Boylan's annually recurring bill to repeal Foundation's charter. B. S. Coler's attack on General Education Board and Dr. Abraham Flexner; controversy over New York City Board of Education's adoption of "Gary Plan" in schools. Relation between Flexner, General Education Board, Rockefeller Foundation, Board of Education, Gary Plan. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller, Edwin R. Embree.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Letters of Appreciation, 1910-1911 (Box 25, Folder 254)
    30A
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Newspaper Clippings, 1908-1913 (Box 25, Folder 255)
    Editorials for and against Foundation.
    30B
  - Rockefeller Foundation - General
    Tributes and thanks to Foundation; employment problems and policies; grants, appeals, recommendations; administrative details; Judson's recommendations regarding policy; gift to Rockefeller Institute; MacKenzie King's report on industrial relations; Foundation's power to make loans; regarding giving to cultural projects; Edwin Embree's quarrel with anti-saloon league; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s hopes for future; International Health Division; Max Mason and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. on policy; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s disagreement with Julius Rosenwald over use of endowment funds; controversy with Dr. Stiles regarding prevalence of hookworm in South; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. urges study of low-cost housing; New York Post attack on Foundation; various committees and their work; education policy; work abroad; relation of Pan-American work with Nelson A. Rockefeller's work; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. on future of Foundation; Foundation position regarding meaning of "advancement of knowledge;" appeals, grants and declinations; Foundation's responsibility for patriotism and morals of its fellows discussed; changes of personnel; Nobel Prizes to officers; question of merging Foundation and General Education Board. Correspondents include Wickliffe Rose, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Harry Pratt Judson, Louis G. Myers, Starr J. Murphy, Frederick T. Gates, Charles O. Heydt, K. Murai, O. D. Young, Thomas M. Debevoise, E. Robinson, Raymond B. Fosdick, Thomas B. Appleget, Norma S. Thompson, Dr. Alan Gregg, Eleanora, Queen of Bulgaria, Arthur W. Packard, Edwin R. Embree, Lindsley F. Kimball, Warren Weaver, Flora M. Rhind, Dana S. Creel, Dean Rusk, Martha Baird Rockefeller.
    30.1
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1913-1918 (Box 25, Folder 256)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1919-1925 (Box 25, Folder 257)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1926-1930 (Box 25, Folder 258)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1931-1932 (Box 25, Folder 259)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1933-1934 (Box 26, Folder 260)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1935-1937 (Box 26, Folder 261)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1938-1939 (Box 26, Folder 262)
    - Not Used (Box 26, Folder 263)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1940 (Box 26, Folder 264)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1941-1943 (Box 26, Folder 265)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1944-1945 (Box 26, Folder 266)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1946-1948 (Box 26, Folder 267)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1946-1948 (Box 26, Folder 0267A)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1949 (Box 27, Folder 268)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1950-1951 (Box 27, Folder 269)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1950-1951 (Box 27, Folder 0269A)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 270)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 0270A)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, January-May 1953 (Box 27, Folder 271)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1953 (Box 27, Folder 0271A)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, June-December 1953 (Box 27, Folder 272)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1954 (Box 27, Folder 273)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, January-March 1955 (Box 27, Folder 274)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, April-December 1955 (Box 27, Folder 275)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1954-1955 (Box 27, Folder 0275A)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 276)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 277)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 278)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 279)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 280)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1958-1960 (Box 28, Folder 0280A)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, January-February 1961 (Box 28, Folder 281)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, March-December 1961 (Box 28, Folder 282)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 0282A)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Taxation, 1910-1920 (Box 29, Folder 283)
    Power of congress; attempt to get federal charter, regarding tax exemption; income tax exemption.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Atterbury Projects, 1916-1918 (Box 29, Folder 284)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest in Grosvenor Atterbury's system of pre-fabricating houses.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Frederick T. Gates Memoranda, 1926-1927 (Box 29, Folder 285)
    "Mr. Swift and the Business Board of the Institute"; "The General Education Board"; "World Philanthropies"; "Thoughts on the Rockefeller Public and Private Benefactions."
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Shanghai Land, 1927-1936 (Box 29, Folder 286)
    Use of Foundation's land in Shanghai by China National Amateur Athletic Federation; Federation's desire to have land. Transfer of land to Shanghai Medical Center.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - 1927 Salary Increase, 1927-1928 (Box 29, Folder 287)
    Officers' salary raised; policy questions.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - 1929 Tax Exemption (Box 29, Folder 288)
    Consolidation of Foundation and Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial; proceedings in New York Supreme Court; affidavit; some correspondence.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Louis G. Myers, 1931-1932 (Box 29, Folder 289)
    His illness and death; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s gift and financial advice for Mrs. Myers; Foundation memorial resolution.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Special Committee on Procedure, 1935 (Box 29, Folder 290)
    Committee grew out of Jerome D. Greene's criticisms incident to ouster of Roger S. Greene from China Medical Board. Considered organization, operation, and procedure of Foundation and its relation to Rockefeller office.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - "History of Foundation Program, 1913-1936" (Box 29, Folder 291)
    Copy with John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s marginalia.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Successor to Lefferts M. Dashiell, 1938 (Box 29, Folder 292)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s desire for older man, ultimate selection of Edward Robinson.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Vivisection Controversy, 1943-1945 (Box 29, Folder 293)
    Protests to Rockefeller Foundation.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondence regarding Resolutions, 1939-1945 (Box 29, Folder 294)
    Brake on spending with regards to current position; limit to amount expendable per annum.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Hendry Trust, 1938-1946 (Box 29, Folder 295)
    Hendry's death and trust; Mrs. Hendry had lifetime use; her death, and transfer of trust to Foundation.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Space at Rockefeller Institute for Foundation's International Health Division, 1945-1947 (Box 29, Folder 296)
    Foundation leased space at Rockefeller Institute for laboratory experiment.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Taxation, 1941-1956 (Box 29, Folder 297)
    Treasury Department questionnaire; exemption. Attack on exemption in House and investigation by Ways and Means Committee; Foundation's defense in regards to excess accumulation of capital gains.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Lists - Trustees of Boards, 1939-1957 (Box 29, Folder 298)
    Foundation, General Education Board, International Education Board; one list of Foundation officers from beginning to 1936.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Lefferts M. Dashiell and Margaret Deyo Dashiell, 1938-1940 (Box 29, Folder 299)
    Lefferts M. Dashiell's death and funeral; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s tributes to him. Financial arrangements.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Memorial Service for Dr. George E. Vincent, 1930-1942 (Box 29, Folder 300)
    Vincent retired, 1930; died, 1941. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s remarks at memorial service.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Change in Letter of Gift to Riverside Church, 1928-1945 (Box 29, Folder 301)
    Foundation, as successor to Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial, acted to liberalize endowment with regard to use of profits.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Endowment Liberalization, 1931-1942 (Box 29, Folder 302)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.-Julius Rosenwald controversy; liberalization of stipulation regarding endowment grants for General Education Board and Foundation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, Thomas M. Debevoise, Thomas B. Appleget, Norma S. Thompson.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Dean Rusk Successor, 1960-1961 (Box 29, Folder 303)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Report of Committee on Appraisal and Plan, 1933-1935 (Box 30, Folder 304)
    Report by Raymond B. Fosdick, Angell and Stewart includes history, finance, general problems, administrative procedures, etc. in regards to programs. Correspondents include Raymond B. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Max Mason.
    30.1B
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Plans for Future Work, March 1945-October 1946 (Box 30, Folder 305)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Plans for Future Work, November 1946-1947 (Box 30, Folder 306)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Plans for Future Work - Reports and Drafts, 1946 (Box 30, Folder 307)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Plans for Future Work - Reports and Drafts, 1946 (Box 30, Folder 308)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Plans for Future Work - Reports and Drafts, 1946 (Box 30, Folder 309)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Plans for Future Work - Reports - Population, 1949-1950 (Box 30, Folder 310)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Dr. George E. Vincent - Correspondence, 1916-1922 (Box 31, Folder 311)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. congratulated on choice of Vincent; administrative details; musicale given by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller for Dr. and Mrs. Vincent at Williamsburg. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s desire to retire from presidency and retain board chairmanship. Hiring of Vincent; re-organization; Jerome D. Greene's resignation; Vincent's attendance at Panama Conference; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s desire for organization charts; Vincent's stay at Ormond Beach; investigation of Belgium War Relief. Question of having a history written. Vincent's trip around world; illness. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Frederick T. Gates, Willard S. Richardson, Thomas M. Debevoise, George E. Vincent, Raymond B. Fosdick.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Dr. George E. Vincent - Correspondence, 1923-1926 (Box 31, Folder 312)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Dr. George E. Vincent - Correspondence, 1927-1941 (Box 31, Folder 313)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Gifts from John D. Rockefeller and Laura Spelman Rockefeller - John D. Rockefeller Deed of Trust, 1913 (Box 31, Folder 314)
    On January 6, 1913, John D. Rockefeller deeded stock to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Jerome D. Greene, and others, to be used for charitable purposes and surrendered to Rockefeller Foundation if it was incorporated. Minutes; transfer to Rockefeller Foundation.
    30.1A
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Gifts from John D. Rockefeller and Laura Spelman Rockefeller - Gift of February 23, 1917 (Box 31, Folder 315)
    John D. Rockefeller gave Standard Oil stock to Foundation; payment of last dividend to John D. Rockefeller. Recapitalization plan in many of Standard Oil companies.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Gifts from John D. Rockefeller and Laura Spelman Rockefeller - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Gifts, 1913-1941 (Box 31, Folder 316)
    Gifts to Baptist organizations primarily, principal to be held by Foundation. Gifts to Foundation from Laura Spelman Rockefeller estate.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Gifts from John D. Rockefeller and Laura Spelman Rockefeller - John D. Rockefeller Gifts, 1913-1949 (Box 31, Folder 317)
    List of John D. Rockefeller's gifts; decisions regarding when and what to give; release of restrictions; reasons for gifts; gifts to Baptist Home for Aged of New York City.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Special Gifts - 1926 Cancellation of Trusts, 1917-1923 (Box 31, Folder 318)
    Question of where to transfer trusts; decision to give organizations a substitute amount of funds in order to release Foundation from its trust duties. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Raymond B. Fosdick, Thomas M. Debevoise, George E. Vincent, Norma S. Thompson.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Special Gifts - 1926 Cancellation of Trusts, 1926-1927 (Box 31, Folder 319)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Reorganization of 1926, 1926-1927 (Box 32, Folder 320)
    Reorganization of Foundation, Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial, General Education Board, China Medical Board, and International Education Board. Correspondents include Raymond B. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, George E. Vincent, Wickliffe Rose, Norma S. Thompson.
    30.1D
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Reorganization of 1926, 1928-1940 (Box 32, Folder 321)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Reorganization of 1926 - Legal Petition and Agreement, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 322)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Christmas Gift - Letters of Appreciation, 1919-1920 (Box 32, Folder 323)
    John D. Rockefeller's gift of $100,000,000 to be split equally between the Rockefeller Foundation and the General Education Board. Gift dubbed "Christmas gift" because it was made on December 24, 1919. Letters of appreciation to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for his father's gift.
    30.1G
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Christmas Gift - Clippings, 1919 (Box 32, Folder 324)
    John D. Rockefeller's gift of $100,000,000 to be split equally between the Rockefeller Foundation and the General Education Board. Gift dubbed "Christmas gift" because it was made on December 24, 1919.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Reports, Bulletins, Articles, 1915-1945 (Box 32, Folder 325)
    30.2
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Reports, Bulletins, Articles, 1946-1947 (Box 32, Folder 326)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Reports, Bulletins, Articles, 1948-1956 (Box 32, Folder 327)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Reports, Bulletins, Articles, 1957-1961 (Box 32, Folder 328)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Reports, 1918, 1920 (Box 32, Folder 329)
    Annual Report, 1918. Annual Report, 1920.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Reports, 1915, 1922, 1923 (Box 33, Folder 330)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Elections and Resignations, 1915 (Box 33, Folder 331)
    Retired trustees' comments on Board policy; retirement of officers. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick, Douglas Freeman, John Foster Dulles.
    30.3
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Elections and Resignations, 1936-1955 (Box 33, Folder 332)
    Retired trustees' comments on Board policy; retirement of officers. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick, Douglas S. Freeman, John Foster Dulles.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Elections and Resignations, 1956-1961 (Box 33, Folder 333)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Elections and Resignations - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Dinner for Trustees, April 4, 1945 (Box 33, Folder 334)
    Informal discussion of Foundation problems.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Elections and Resignations - Raymond B. Fosdick Retirement, 1948-1953 (Box 33, Folder 335)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s tribute to Fosdick at Trustees meeting.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Elections and Resignations - Chester Barnard Retirement, 1948-1951 (Box 33, Folder 336)
    Selection of Dean Rusk as successor.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Elections and Resignations - Retirement from Boards, 1928-1951 (Box 33, Folder 337)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and John D. Rockefeller 3rd tributes to retiring Trustees.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Elections and Resignations - John D. Rockefeller 3rd Election as Chairman, 1952-1953 (Box 33, Folder 338)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, 1917-1938 (Box 33, Folder 339)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick, John Foster Dulles, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., E. M. Hopkins.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Meetings, 1925-1961 (Box 34, Folder 340)
    Arrangements for meetings. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Meetings - 1940 Williamsburg Meeting (Box 34, Folder 341)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Nominations, 1936-1939 (Box 34, Folder 342)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick, Arthur W. Packard.
    30.3A
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Nominations, 1953-1961 (Box 34, Folder 343)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, William I. Myers, Benjamin M. McKelway, Dean Rusk.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Nominations, 1961 (Box 34, Folder 0343A)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Nominations - Williamsburg, 1959-1960 (Box 34, Folder 344)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Requests, Permission and Acknowledgements Regarding Nominations of New Board Members, 1936-1940 (Box 34, Folder 345)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Max Mason Resignation, 1928, 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 346)
    Policy discussions regarding committee organizations; Mason's decision to resign. Tributes to Mason; selection of Raymond B. Fosdick as successor. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Jerome D. Greene, Raymond B. Fosdick, Max Mason.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Resignation, April 1940 (Box 34, Folder 347)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s remarks upon resigning as chairman of Foundation; comments on his remarks. Tributes to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    30.3B
  - Rockefeller Foundation - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Resignation, April 1940, 1940, 1949 (Box 34, Folder 348)